Takyoung Kim

Ph.D. Student at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign (UIUC)

Thomas M. Siebel Center for Computer Science, MC-258, 201 North Goodwin Avenue, Urbana, IL 61801

③ youngerous.github.io ☑ tk30@illinois.edu in in/youngerous ➢ Google Scholar

Interests

My research interest lies in the intersection of Natural Language Processing and Communication. I am particularly interested in building communicative language models (LMs) that can understand social and cognitive context, evaluating preference during interactions, and exploring how LMs compose knowledge both from parametric and external sources.

Education

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Urbana, IL, USA

Aug 2024 - Present

Doctor of Philosophy, Computer Science

Advisor: Dilek Hakkani-Tür

Korea University, Seoul, South Korea

Sep 2020 - Aug 2022

Master of Engineering, Industrial Management Engineering Advisor: Pilsung Kang (now at Seoul National University)

Thesis: Relaxing Unrealistic Assumptions of Dataset and Evaluation Metric in Dialogue State Tracking

Sungkyunkwan University, Seoul, South Korea 🗹

Mar 2013 - Aug 2020

Bachelor of Science in Engineering, Interdisciplinary Program of Convergent Software Bachelor of Media & Communication (Leave of absence for military service: Feb 2015 - Nov 2016)

Publications

* indicates equal contribution

Revealing User Familiarity Bias in Task-Oriented Dialogue via Interactive Evaluation Takyoung Kim, Jamin Shin, Young-Ho Kim, Sanghwan Bae, Sungdong Kim

Workshop on NLP for Conversational AI (Oral, Best Paper Award)

NLP4ConvAI, ACL 2024

DSTEA: Improving Dialogue State Tracking via Entity Adaptive Pre-training Yukyung Lee, Takyoung Kim, Hoonsang Yoon, Pilsung Kang, Junseong Bang, Misuk Kim Knowledge-Based Systems (Q1, Impact Factor: 8.8) Workshop on Knowledge Augmented Methods for NLP

KBS 2024

KnowledgeNLP, KDD 2023

KoSBi: A Dataset for Mitigating Social Bias Risks Towards Safer Large Language Model Applications Hwaran Lee*, Seokhee Hong*, Joonsuk Park, Takyoung Kim, Gunhee Kim, Jung-Woo Ha Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Industry Track) ACL 2023

SQuARe: A Large-Scale Dataset of Sensitive Questions and Acceptable Responses Created Through Human-Machine Collaboration **□** </>

Hwaran Lee*, Seokhee Hong*, Joonsuk Park, Takyoung Kim, Meeyoung Cha, Yejin Choi, Byoungpil Kim, Gunhee Kim, Eun-Ju Lee, Yong Lim, Alice Oh, Sangchul Park, Jung-Woo Ha Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Oral, Best Paper Nomination) ACL 2023

- Oh My Mistake!: Toward Realistic Dialgoue State Tracking including Turnback Utterances Takyoung Kim, Yukyung Lee, Hoonsang Yoon, Pilsung Kang, Junseong Bang, Misuk Kim Towards Semi-Supervised and Reinforced Task-Oriented Dialog Systems SereTOD, EMNLP 2022
- Mismatch between Multi-turn Dialogue and its Evaluation Metric in Dialogue State Tracking 🖹 <u>Takyoung Kim</u>, Hoonsang Yoon, Yukyung Lee, Pilsung Kang, Misuk Kim Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Short) ACL 2022
- Building an Integrated Framework of Korean Text Summarization and Text-to-Speech Takyoung Kim, Jina Kim, Hyeongwon Kang, Subin Kim, Pilsung Kang Journal of Korean Institute of Industrial Engineers **JKIIE 2022**

Preprint & Under Review

Learning to Explore and Select for Coverage-Conditioned Retrieval-Augmented Generation Takyoung Kim, Kyungjae Lee, Young Rok Jang, Ji Yong Cho, Gangwoo Kim, Minseok Cho, Moontae Lee Preprint

Research Experience

Research Experience	
University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Conversational AI Lab Urbana, IL, USA Graduate Research Assistant (Advisor: Dilek Hakkani-Tür) Working on cognitive interactions in embodied environments	Aug 2024 - Presen
Korea University Data Science & Business Analytics Lab Seoul, South Korea Research Associate (Advisor: Pilsung Kang) Worked on retrieval-augmented language models specialized in Korean digital media	Apr 2024 - Jul 2024
LG AI Research Advanced Machine Learning Lab Seoul, South Korea ☑ Research Intern (Mentors: Kyungjae Lee, Moontae Lee) Worked on improving long-form responses of retrieval-augmented language models via planning	Apr 2023 - Mar 202
NAVER AI Lab Language Research Team Seongnam, South Korea Research Intern (Mentor: Sungdong Kim) Worked on revealing innate bias in task-oriented dialogue research via interactive study [1] Worked on constructing safety benchmark for sensitive questions [4] and social biases [3]	Jul 2022 - Jan 2023
Korea University Data Science & Business Analytics Lab Seoul, South Korea Graduate Research Assistant (Advisor: Pilsung Kang) Worked on analyzing realistic biases and limitations of dialogue state tracking [6, 5, 2] Developed algorithms and pipelines in various domains, such as news [7], car, and ocean waves	Sep 2020 - Jun 2022
Korea University Data Science & Business Analytics Lab Seoul, South Korea Undergraduate Research Intern (Advisor: Pilsung Kang) Designed spatial/temporal architecture reflecting optical flow for video deepfake detection	Jan 2020 - Aug 2020
Presentations and Talks	
Selective Masking for Task-Adaptive Pre-Training Korean Institute of Industrial Engineers Conference (Spring)	Jun 202
A Life of Turning into Software Software Edu Fest, Naver Connect Foundation	Jul 2020
Honors and Awards	
CS PhD Fellowship University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign	Aug 2024 - May 202
Best Paper Award ACL 2024 NLP for Conversational AI Workshop	Aug 202
Best Student Feedback Award, Research Ideation Contest Korea University	Feb 2021, Dec 202
2nd Place (2,500 USD), MyData Acting Hackathon Ministry of Science and ICT	Oct 201
Merit-based Scholarship, Computer Science Coursework Sungkyunkwan University	Spring 2018, Fall 201
Feaching Experience	
T02459101 Natural Language Processing Hankuk University of Foreign Studies Teaching Assistant (Instructor: Yukyung Lee)	Feb 2024 - Jun 202
Industrial Machine Learning LG Electronics	Jan 2022 - Apr 202
Head Teaching Assistant (Instructor: Pilsung Kang)	
Head Teaching Assistant (Instructor: Pilsung Kang) Research Mentoring Hyundai Mobis Research Project Assistant (Instructor: Pilsung Kang)	Jul 2021 - Sep 202

Academic Service

Conference Reviewer	
Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)	2024
Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)	2024
Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) - Industry Track	2023 - 2024
Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)	2023 - 2024
Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) - Datasets & Benchmarks	2022 - 2024
Journal Reviewer	
Knowledge-Based Systems	2023 - 2024
Others	
ACL Rolling Review (ARR)	2023 - 2024